# Xiaochuan Ai

XiaochuanAi9@outlook.com

**SUMMARY** 

While studying professional courses, I participated in Internet+, student innovation projects, research projects and professional related discipline competitions. I am a good listener, flexible and reliable character in the team. As the project progressed, teamwork and self-learning skills were greatly enhanced.

### **EDUCATION**

**University:** Xi'an Technological University Major: **Computer Science and Technology** 

Sept-2020 to July-2024

Phone: (0086) 15291502985

Major Ranking: 4% Class Rank: 1st GPA:3.5

A CSP for the identification of glass artifacts based on a systematic clustering approach to be published.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## ICT Competition 2022-2023 China Shaanxi Province Practice Final

Dece-11-2022

- In one month, learned about data communication, security, WLAN, including routing protocols, Layer 2 switching technology, IPv6, VPN technology, etc.
- Won the first prize of the individual competition
- Won the provincial second prize of the undergraduate network track individual competition.

### Innovation and entrepreneurship training program for college students

May-2022 to October-2023

- Based on the PyTorch framework, artificial intelligence algorithms are used to identify whether people are wearing masks correctly on specific occasions. After capturing and identifying, the feedback data is transferred to the Mini Program module, and after analysis, the external voice prompt device is linked to play the warning voice.
- From scratch, learn to make mini programs using the uniapp framework.
- As one of the project leaders, successfully established a school-level project.

## 2022 National Collegiate Mathematical Modeling Competition

Sept-15-2022 to Sept-18-2022

- won the first prize in the school competition In April.
- From July to September, a two-month intensive training was held. Problem analysis, model building, thesis writing and team coordination skills have been greatly improved.

## Participated in the computer vision project team of the joint PhD project team of HKUST and CMU for research April-29-2023 to present

- Research content: Develop large-scale human models by collecting a large number of text images weakly related to human information. Use these data to train a generic backbone for human body-related tasks such as visual transformers (VIT), augmenting various human body-related tasks such as 2D and 3D human pose estimation, human segmentation and reconstruction.
- Main project involved: Speech To Gestures. The project content uses audio as the only input signal to generate realistic, coherent and diverse 3D whole body movements, and body motions, combined with facial expressions, and gestures. Expected to produce a paper in the summer.

### AWARD&CERTIFICATE

First prize of ICT competition at school level.

October-2022 December-2022

Second prize of Huawei ICT Competition Shaanxi Division

2022-2023 Second Class Academic Scholarship.

**Sept-2021 to Sept-2022** 

2022 school level Merit student.

**Sept-2021 to Sept-2022** 

Third prize of the China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling.	April-2022